Guide to the Time Inc. Real Estate Division Records 1960-1980 MS 3009-RG 23
New-York Historical Society
Time Inc. Real Estate Division Records
1960-1980
New-York Historical Society
Time, inc.
MS 3009-RG 23
7 Linear feet in 6 record cartons, 1 flat box
The Time Inc. Real Estate Division Records contain files on building and land purchases, construction, and alternations for offices and other facilities of Time Inc. and its subsidiaries.
Arrangement Note
Organized alphabetically.
Access Restrictions
Open to qualified researchers with the exception of restricted materials. Restricted materials may include privileged attorney correspondence; personnel performance evaluations; contracts and agreements; and records with personally identifiable information. Restricted materials are located in box R11. Materials created within the past 35 years also may be subject to restriction on a case-by-case basis. Materials are stored offsite and advance notice is required for use.
Related Archival Materials Note
This finding aid relates to just one record group of the Time Inc. Records. For information about the other record groups and for overall information about the archives, please see the Guide to the Time Inc. Records (MS 3009). The Henry Luce Papers (MS 3014) were acquired with the Time Inc. Records. The collection of books acquired with the records are cataloged as the Time Inc. Reference Library. Additional files on Time Inc. office buildings are in Time Inc. Subject Files (MS 3009-RG 1) and Time Inc. Reference Files (MS 3009-RG 3).
Scope and Contents Note
The Time Inc. Real Estate Division Records include files from vice president Peter Hopkins and manager Jerome Justin on building and land purchases, and construction of or alterations to for offices, laboratories, warehouses, and other facilities of Time Inc. and its subsidiaries. Records include blueprints and other technical drawings; invoices; interoffice memoranda; inspection reports; estimates; safety code manuals; feasibility studies; correspondence from construction companies and architects; approval letters listing work done; board meeting minutes regarding construction; bidder lists; and construction specifications. Companies that Time Inc. worked with on building projects include J. Robert Carlton and Associates and Carl M. Geupel Construction Company.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Time Inc. in 2015.
Blueprints (reprographic copies); Corporation records.; Technical drawings.; Organization files.; Corporations -- History.; Corporations -- New York (State) -- New York.; Floor plans.; Real property -- Connecticut.; Real property -- Illinois.; Real property -- Indiana.; Real property -- New York (State); Time, inc. -- Archives.; Time, inc. -- Buildings.; Time, inc. -- History.
- Chicago: New Building: Approval Letters, 1966-1972 (Offsite-box 764, Folder 1-2)
- Chicago: New Building: Change orders, 1968-1971 (Offsite-box 764, Folder 3-6)
- Chicago: New Building: Cafeteria, 1968-1969 (Offsite-box 764, Folder 7)
- Chicago: New Building: Contractor selection, 1966-1967 (Offsite-box 764, Folder 8)
- Chicago: New Building: Contractor selection [RESTRICTED] (Offsite-box R11, Folder 1)
- Chicago: New Building: Cost estimating, 1967-1969 (Offsite-box 764, Folder 9-10)
- Chicago: New Building: I.S.D., 1966-1967 (Offsite-box 764, Folder 11)
- Chicago: New Building: Job Meetings, 1969-1972 (Offsite-box 764, Folder 12-13)
- Chicago: New Building: Materials handling (DASOL), 1967-1970 (Offsite-box 764, Folder 14)
- Chicago: New Building: Miscellaneous: Construction, 1967-1971 (Offsite-box 764, Folder 15-16)
- Chicago: New Building: Mock-up, 1967-1968 (Offsite-box 765, Folder 1)
- Chicago: New Building: Mock-up [RESTRICTED] (Offsite-box R11, Folder 2)
- Chicago: New Building: Progress report, 1969-1972 (Offsite-box 765, Folder 2)
- Chicago: New Building: Schedule, 1967 (Offsite-box 765, Folder 3)
- Chicago: New Building: Specifications, 1967-1968 (Offsite-box 765, Folder 4)
- Indianapolis: Silver Burdett: General, 1963-1964 (Offsite-box 765, Folder 5-7)
- Indianapolis: Silver Burdett: Architect, 1965 (Offsite-box 765, Folder 8)
- Indianapolis: Silver Burdett: The Austin Company, 1963 (Offsite-box 765, Folder 9-11)
- Indianapolis: Silver Burdett: Bids and prices, 1962-1964 (Offsite-box 765, Folder 12)
- Indianapolis: Silver Burdett: Board memos, 1963-1967 (Offsite-box 765, Folder 14)
- Indianapolis: Silver Burdett: Budgets and forecasts, 1969 (Offsite-box 765, Folder 15)
- Indianapolis: Silver Burdett: Building costs, 1963-1964 (Offsite-box 765, Folder 16)
- Indianapolis: Silver Burdett: Change orders, 1964-1965 (Offsite-box 765, Folder 17)
- Indianapolis: Silver Burdett: Contract documents and specifications [RESTRICTED], 1964 (Offsite-box R11, Folder 3)
- Indianapolis: Silver Burdett: Construction, 1963-1967 (Offsite-box 765, Folder 18-19)
- Indianapolis: Silver Burdett: Construction payments, 1963-1965 (Offsite-box 765, Folder 20-25)
- Indianapolis: Silver Burdett: Construction payments not vouchered by Geupel, 1964-1965 (Offsite-box 766, Folder 1)
- Indianapolis: Silver Burdett: Construction Payments, 1965 (Offsite-box 766, Folder 2)
- Indianapolis: Silver Burdett: Cost summary, 1963-1964 (Offsite-box 766, Folder 3)
- Indianapolis: Silver Burdett: Design, 1963-1966 (Offsite-box 766, Folder 4-5)
- Indianapolis: Silver Burdett: Drake Startzman revised layout, 1963 (Offsite-box 766, Folder 6)
- Indianapolis: Silver Burdett: Electrical, 1964 (Offsite-box 766, Folder 7)
- Indianapolis: Silver Burdett: Financial, 1962-1968 (Offsite-box 766, Folder 8)
- Indianapolis: Silver Burdett: Fire protection, 1963-1968 (Offsite-box 766, Folder 9)
- Indianapolis: Silver Burdett: Garbage dump, proposed, 1965 (Offsite-box 766, Folder 10)
- Indianapolis: Silver Burdett: Geupel, 1963-1967 (Offsite-box 766, Folder 11-12)
- Indianapolis: Silver Burdett: Geupel contract file, 1963-1968 (Offsite-box 766, Folder 13)
- Indianapolis: Silver Burdett: Geupel contract file [RESTRICTED] (Offsite-box R11, Folder 4)
- Indianapolis: Silver Burdett: Geupel fee, 1963-1965 (Offsite-box 766, Folder 14)
- Indianapolis: Silver Burdett: HVAC, 1964-1966 (Offsite-box 766, Folder 15)
- Indianapolis: Silver Burdett: Insurance, 1963-1967 (Offsite-box 766, Folder 16)
- Indianapolis: Silver Burdett: Legal [RESTRICTED], 1963-1966 (Offsite-box R11, Folder 5)
- Indianapolis: Silver Burdett: Maps, undated (Offsite-box 766, Folder 17)
- Indianapolis: Silver Burdett: Mechanical, 1964 (Offsite-box 766, Folder 18)
- Indianapolis: Silver Burdett: Miscellaneous, 1963-1966 (Offsite-box 766, Folder 19)
- Indianapolis: Silver Burdett: Morristown, 1966 (Offsite-box 766, Folder 20-21)
- Indianapolis: Silver Burdett: Morristown (Offsite-box 1481, Folder 3)
- Indianapolis: Silver Burdett: Plans and study drawings, undated (Offsite-box 766, Folder 22-24)
- Indianapolis: Silver Burdett: Plot plans and site plans, 1963 (Offsite-box 766, Folder 25-26)
- Indianapolis: Silver Burdett: Plot plans and site plans (Offsite-box 1481, Folder 4)
- Indianapolis: Silver Burdett: Publicity, 1963-1964 (Offsite-box 766, Folder 27)
- Indianapolis: Silver Burdett: Punch List, 1964 (Offsite-box 766, Folder 28)
- Indianapolis: Silver Burdett: Rapistan, 1964 (Offsite-box 766, Folder 29)
- Indianapolis: Silver Burdett: Samples, 1964 (Offsite-box 767, Folder 1)
- Indianapolis: Silver Burdett: Schedule, 1964 (Offsite-box 767, Folder 2)
- Indianapolis: Silver Burdett: Sewer, 1966 (Offsite-box 767, Folder 3)
- Indianapolis: Silver Burdett: Shop drawings, 1964 (Offsite-box 767, Folder 4-7)
- Indianapolis: Silver Burdett: Shopping center (proposed), 1965-1966 (Offsite-box 767, Folder 8)
- Indianapolis: Silver Burdett: Shopping center (proposed) [RESTRICTED] (Offsite-box R11, Folder 6)
- Indianapolis: Silver Burdett: Sign, 1964 (Offsite-box 767, Folder 9)
- Indianapolis: Silver Burdett: Warehouse analysis, 1963 (Offsite-box 767, Folder 10)
- Indianapolis: Silver Burdett: Warehouse property, 1965 (Offsite-box 767, Folder 11)
- Indianapolis: Silver Burdett: Warehouse (study), 1963 (Offsite-box 767, Folder 12)
- Indianapolis: Silver Burdett: Zoning, 1967-1968 (Offsite-box 767, Folder 13)
- Mexico: Lomas Verdes, 1967 (Offsite-box 767, Folder 14)
- Silver Burdett: Addition: Advertising, 1967 (Offsite-box 767, Folder 15)
- Silver Burdett: Addition: Board memos, 1967-1968 (Offsite-box 767, Folder 16)
- Silver Burdett: Addition: Bulletins and change orders [FOLDER IN CONSERVATION], 1967-1968 (Offsite-box 767, Folder 17)
- Silver Burdett: Addition: Census Bureau progress report, 1967 (Offsite-box 767, Folder 18)
- Silver Burdett: Addition: Construction, 1967-1968 (Offsite-box 767, Folder 19)
- Silver Burdett: Addition: Cost Reports, 1968-1969 (Offsite-box 767, Folder 20)
- Silver Burdett: Addition: Design, 1967-1968 (Offsite-box 767, Folder 21)
- Silver Burdett: Addition: Estimates & prices, 1967-1968 (Offsite-box 767, Folder 22)
- Silver Burdett: Addition: Fire protection, 1967-1969 (Offsite-box 767, Folder 23-24)
- Silver Burdett: Addition: Specifications, 1967 (Offsite-box 767, Folder 25)
- Springdale [Connecticut]: Peabody Galion, 1970-1971 (Offsite-box 767, Folder 26)
- Springdale [Connecticut]: Peabody Galion [RESTRICTED] (Offsite-box R11, Folder 8)
- Springdale [Connecticut]: Property sold to A&F Builders, Inc., 1965 (Offsite-box 767, Folder 27)
- Springdale [Connecticut]: Property sold to A&F Builders, Inc. [RESTRICTED] (Offsite-box R11, Folder 9)
- Springdale [Connecticut]: Sale of property to Donnelley, 1968-1969 (Offsite-box 767, Folder 28)
- Springdale [Connecticut]: Sale of property to Donnelley [RESTRICTED] (Offsite-box R11, Folder 10)
- Springdale [Connecticut]: 1 Communication Plaza lease, 1970-1972 (Offsite-box 768, Folder 1)
- Springdale [Connecticut]: 1 Communication Plaza lease [RESTRICTED] (Offsite-box R11, Folder 11)
- Springdale [Connecticut]: Lease and relocation, 1970 (Offsite-box 768, Folder 2-3)
- Springdale [Connecticut]: Lease and relocation [RESTRICTED] (Offsite-box R11, Folder 12)
- Springdale [Connecticut]: Sale, 1970 (Offsite-box 768, Folder 4)
- Springdale [Connecticut]: Sale [RESTRICTED] (Offsite-box R11, Folder 7)
- Time and Life Building: Amsterdam, 1968-1969 (Offsite-box 768, Folder 5-7)
- Time: Ficker/Wrather, 1973-1976 (Offsite-box 768, Folder 8)
- Time: Ficker/Wrather [RESTRICTED] (Offsite-box R11, Folder 13)
- Time: Hilton Head: July 24-25, 1972 (Offsite-box 768, Folder 9a)
- Time: Plaza, 1964-1975 (Offsite-box 768, Folder 9b)
- Time: Sports Illustrated Resort: Wrather, 1973-1974 (Offsite-box 768, Folder 10)
- Time: Sports Illustrated Resort: Wrather [RESTRICTED] (Offsite-box R11, Folder 14)
- Time: Rome Building Possibility, 1965-1966 (Offsite-box 768, Folder 11)
- Time Inc.: Teaneck: Family publications, 1966-1975 (Offsite-box 768, Folder 12-13)
- Time Inc.: Teaneck: Family publications [RESTRICTED] (Offsite-box R11, Folder 15)
- Time: Tehran, 1975 (Offsite-box 768, Folder 14)
- Time: Upper Saddle River, 1972-1974 (Offsite-box 768, Folder 15)
- Time: Upper Saddle River [RESTRICTED] (Offsite-box R11, Folder 16-17)
- Time: W.F.T. Incorporation, 1974-1975 (Offsite-box 768, Folder 16)
- Time: W.F.T. Incorporation [RESTRICTED] (Offsite-box R11, Folder 18)
- Washington, D.C., 1965-1966 (Offsite-box 768, Folder 17-18)
- Washington, D.C. (Offsite-box 1481, Folder 5)
- WFBM: General, 1966-1970 (Offsite-box 769, Folder 1)
- WFBM: General [RESTRICTED] (Offsite-box R11, Folder 19)
- WFBM: Studio expansion: Architects, 1965 (Offsite-box 769, Folder 2)
- WFBM: Studio expansion: Bids and prices, 1965-1966 (Offsite-box 769, Folder 3)
- WFBM: Studio expansion: Contract, 1965-1966 (Offsite-box 769, Folder 4)
- WFBM: Studio expansion: Contract [RESTRICTED] (Offsite-box R11, Folder 20)
- WFBM: Studio expansion: Construction, 1964-1967 (Offsite-box 769, Folder 5)
- WFBM: Studio expansion: Design, 1965 (Offsite-box 769, Folder 6)
- WFBM: Studio expansion: Mechanical and electrical, 1965-1966 (Offsite-box 769, Folder 7)
- WFBM: Studio expansion: Meeting reports, 1965-1966 (Offsite-box 769, Folder 8)
- WFBM: Studio expansion: Plans, 1965-1966 (Offsite-box 769, Folder 9-11)
- WFBM: Studio expansion: Contract summary, 1967 (Offsite-box 769, Folder 12)